Kush Kumar Dhawan

E-Mail: kushkumardhawan@gmail.com Mobile: +91-9459619235

CAREER PROFILE

An engineering graduate more than 4 years of experience in programming and Software Development

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Software Development: Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) (C#)

Mobile Development: Android Development (JAVA), Windows 10 Universal Apps (C#)

Wearable Development: Android Wear SDK, Pebble

Web Development: ASP. Net, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQUERY

Designing and Wire Framing: Adobe Illustrator

Databases: MS SQL Server, SQLite

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, UNIX

Tools: Visual Studio, Android Studio, XCode, Sublime text, MS SQL Server, Aptana Studio

PERSONAL SKILLS

- · Good communication skills
- Good leadership skills
- · Fast learner
- · Team player
- Possess skills to meet clients, understanding Client Requirement and preparing an outline of project
- Extensive capacity to work and adapt successfully in any kind of situation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- June 2015 till date Accenture
- January 2015 till May 2015- NextGen Media Operations (NeMo Technologies PVT)
- August 2013 till January 2015 SBL India (Kakkanad, Cochin)
- April 2012 till July 2013 Working with Public Health Foundation Of India (New Delhi)
- · January 2010 December 2011 Set up own firm for developing websites and web solutions
- January 2009 January 2011 Worked as a freelancer

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

2012- Degree in computer science from Chitkara University.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded by the Speaker (Shri. Brij Bihari Lal Butail) of Vidhan Sabha Himachal Pradesh for developing and implementing India's first e Vidhan System in Himachal Pradesh (India), 2014.
- National finalist, Microsoft imagine cup 2011 (https://teamsoch.wordpress.com/)

Wash Warran Pharman

ORGANISATIONAL SCAN AND KEY DELIVERABLES

Accenture

Technical ConsultantMay 2015 till date

Projects

ANDROID DEVELOPMENT

Himachal Parking

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=findparking.hp.dit.himachal.com.shimlaparking)

Parking Manager

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=parkingmanager.hp.dit.himachal.com.hpparkingmanager)

HPSRDH (Himachal Pradesh State Resident Data Hub)

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=in.gov.hp.Aadhaar_HP.SRDH)

Anganwadi Monitoring Application

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dithp.aadhaar.HP_AEMC)

HPSSC (Himachal Pradesh Staff Selection Commission)

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=hp.dit.hpsssb.aadhaar.com.hpssc)

Aadhaar Attendance (Biometric Application)

Roles:-

- Worked on Restful Services (JSON)
- Creating WCF Restful services using MS SQL Server
- Designing of the Application using Adobe Illustrator
- My Roles:- Complete Design, Creating Restful Web Services, Mobile Application Deployment and Service Deployment on Windows Server

Web Designing

HPSSC Web Application (http://hpsssb.hp.gov.in/)

Aadhaar Web Application (http://aadhaar.hp.gov.in/)

Roles:-

- Designing and Wire framing of the Application using Adobe Illustrator (Wire framing)
- Implementing the designs using HTML, JS and CSS
- Worked on Responsive designing frameworks (Bootstrap)

NextGen - NeMo Technologies PVT. Android Application Developer

January 2015 till May 2015

- Design and Implementation of Android Wear Application (LG g Watch and Moto 360)
- Worked extensively on Custom Controls , Widgets
- Using the Wear Library
- Working on an Android Application (NextGen Sentinel) (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=nextgensentinel.ngtech.co.uk)

SBL India (Kakkanad Cochin) Software Engineer and Mobile Application Developer

August 2013 till January 2015

- eVidhan (Microsoft Technologies + WPF)
- Designing and Implementation of the software according to the client needs
- Worked extensively on Custom Controls ,TCP/IP Socket Programming
- Extensively worked on the Notes Module (creating notes, sending notes between Members, Ministers and the Secretaries during session)
- Same solution implemented on Android Device using the S-Pen SDK (Samsung)
- Android Application (eVidhan Grievance)
- https://bitbucket.org/MagneticKush/android-app
- The application is used to post the grievance by the public people to their representative (Member or Minister based on Constituency). The general public can post photos and videos related to their issues.
- Worked on the User Interface, Network calls, Logics and Restful Web APIS
- Android Application (eVidhan Proceedings)
- The Application is used to get the Proceeding, List of Business of the selected date and display it on the Mobile Device. This application is specifically designed for the MLA's, Ministers and the Secretariats of the State.
- · Worked on the User Interface, Network calls

Public Health Foundation of India Mobile Application Developer

April 2012 till July 2013

SWASTHYA SLATE (Android) (www.swasthyaslate.org)

Brief: Swasthya Slate is a powerful device that allows Android Tablets and Phones to conduct a limited number of diagnostic tests on the mobile device. The Swasthya Slate includes specialized applications that help users perform a variety of screenings and health analysis protocols. It allows users to deliver fast and accurate care at home, in clinics and just about anywhere. It contains decision support tools to enable users to deliver quality recommendations for achieving better health. The slate stores electronic medical records both locally on the phone/tablet and also pushes the data onto our cloud. This allows offline/online operations and doctor on call services.

Applications Include (http://www.swasthyaslate.org/apps.php)

- Patient Registration Application
- Swasthya Slate Application

- Antenatal Care Application
- Intranatal Care Application
- Cardio Vascular Screening Application

ORGANISATIONAL SCAN AND KEY DELIVERABLES

- Nutrition Application
- Dai Maa Application
- Patient History
- Decision Support
- Health Communication

TEMPERATURE LOGGER (logger.swasthyaslate.org)

Brief: The Temperature Logger is an affordable, SIM enabled device which automatically records, reports and monitors the temperature of vaccines in individual pieces of cold chain equipment, and sends the data to a cloud server.

PHSL (Public Health Scripting Language)

Implemented a smart solution to reduce the paperwork of the Health Worker.

Sypha, Chitkara University Developer and co-founder

August '2009 till December '2010

- Sypha started as web solutions providing company, the company provided solutions for web hosting, website development and
 customized solutions.
- Started Operations in and around Shimla and Mandi regions, Himachal Pradesh.
- · Worked as a UI designer HTML, CSS and Logo Designing.
- Took care of providing hosting solutions, estimating the resource usage for various clients, preparing deadlines.

Research and Development Projects

Public Health Foundation of India (New Delhi)

Worked under Dr. Kanav Kahol and Prof. K. Srinath Reddy.

- Learned about the Design phases of the products and the different types of use cases that must be followed in order to design a product.
- Development, Deployment and Testing of the entire Swasthya Slate Module
- Created a Scaling algorithm to run a single android application to all the mobile Devices (Phones, T.V. etc.)
- Created an algorithm to distinguish different colors using a camera.
- Real time testing of the devices (Swasthya Slate and Temperature Logger)
- Testing of Medical Devices (Blood Pressure machine, Blood Glucose Machines, Digital Thermometers etc.)

MOBILE HEALTH TECHNOLOGY IN INDIA (Research) and Dai Maa

- Developed under the guidance of Dr.Kanav Kahol
 Done a general survey, in the local PHC/CHC s in what all problems they are facing and what are the common Diseases in their nearby villages.
- Dai Maa application is a multi-Lingual Application based on such a Survey.

Android and Wearable's

Created a Generic Solution for the health workers (questionnaire Application PHSL), to digitalize the real time data, and to save time

INTERNSHIPS

Alcatel Lucent MS, Shimla

Two months

Developed a trace decoder for ISUP protocol, was a generic solution to help sort out large traces from the MSC protocol.

Public Health Foundation of India, New Delhi Six months

MOBILE HEALTH TECHNOLOGY IN INDIA (Research):

Presented a Research Paper showing the impact of technology on the Medical Science and how technology can be made more affordable in the field of Medicine. Done the entire work under the guidance of Dr. Kanav Kahol and Dr. K.S.Reddy.

Dai Maa Application Android:

This is an app that enables just in time education for healthcare workers. It allows healthcare workers to scan a device or drug and gets to a website that delivers them content on how to use the medical device or drug. This app also allows healthcare workers to network with each other by uploading questions on use or answering other member's questions. It is coded in Hindi which is a national language in India. The application later became the part of Swasthya Slate. **Chitkara University (H.P.) Research and Development CU STORE:** Six months

Created an Inventory software for the University to keep a record of all the goods.

OTHER PROJECTS

Ecotweet, Microsoft Imagine Cup 2010

Developed a software to help achieve sustainable development, the aim was to create a framework for helping like -minded people come together and able to tackle real world challenges. Language used - c# 3.5. Top 14 teams India.

Prithvi's Hellion, Microsoft Imagine Cup 2011

Developed and researched on an embedded solution that helps automate growing plants. The device was connected to external sensors and all this can be monitored using a windows phone. Technology used - C# 3.5, Windows phone 7, WinCE 6.0. National Finalist in the competition; awarded with a cash prize and invited to speak at Microsoft Gurgaon.

Vehicle Tracking System (2013)

Created an Android Application which gives the real time GPS co-ordinates of the vehicle after some specific time.

Blog

creating a simple web application using Ruby on rails open framework. The application is currently hosted on open source server. http://uncleblog.herokuapp.com/. The application uses PostgreSQL SQL in its backend. This is just a hobby project.

Guest House Booking Application (2015)

- Design and Implementation of Android Application (Guest House)
- Worked on Restful Services (JSON)
- Creating WCF Restful services using MS SQL Server
- · Designing of the Application using Adobe Illustrator
- My Roles:- Complete Design , Creating Restful Web Services , Mobile Application Deployment and Service Deployment on Windows Server
- The application is created as a Hobby project and can be used as Hotel booking application

Donate Smiles (2015)

Design and Implementation of Android Application (Donate-Smile)

- It's an open source application
- The application is created as a Hobby project

TRAININGS ATTENDED

- Foundations of Programming: Fundamentals "Lynda.com" License 022878
- C/C++ Essential Training "Lynda.com" License AFA35D
- Six Weeks Training on Web Application Architecture (Coursera)

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Reading
- Swimming
- Playing Basketball
- Listening Music
- Running